# Joseph Liang, OTR/L

# Software Engineer

🔾 San Francisco, CA 🔀 josephliang@outlook.com 🕜 jgoteam.github.io 🕻 jgoteam

# **PROFILE**

I'm a full-stack Software Engineer with multiple years of experience with JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, Go, and Python. Previously, I was a Psychiatric Occupational Therapist, where equanimity, adaptability, and strong communications skills were critical. Patient and stubbornly curious, I am passionate about clear systematic thinking and the power of persistent, intentioned effort.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Syncosaurus** $\square$

2024 - present

- Created Syncosaurus, an open-source, serverless framework for real-time, collaborative applications
- Designed, prototyped and contributed to key features of Syncosaurus's synchronization engine, including delta updates, message batching, automatic persistence, and connection state recovery
- Engineered a token-based authentication interface to secure HTTP and Websocket traffic
- Built a Node.js CLI to initialize, integrate, develop, manage, and deploy Syncosaurus projects, including an automated provisioning of Cloudflare infrastrucuture
- Developed an analytics dashboard with a custom GraphQL backend, allowing developers to easily visualize and monitor hourly time-series usage and error metrics
- Wrote the documentation, which includes an in-depth breakdown of core Syncosaurus concepts
- Authored a comprehensive case study on Syncosaurus's problem domain, use case, design decisions, and key engineering challenges, readable at https://syncosaurus.github.io/case-study ☑

#### Software Engineer, Self-employed

2022 - present

Developed open-source web applications with technologies such as JavaScript, Node.js, TypeScript, Go, Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Jest, React, CSS, and HTML. Selected projects include:

- Request Bucket: Tool for receiving, organizing, and debugging webhooks (Typescript, React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Nginx, DO droplet)
- MemDeck: Deck memorization toolkit app, with deck customization, record persistence, and a training mode (Ruby, Sinatra, ERB, PostgreSQL)

# **Occupational Therapist**, *Telecare*, *LCCA*, *Lifespan Therapy*

2017 - 2022

- Designed, planned, and led the first occupational therapy program in a psychiatric health facility
- Conducted OT evaluations, developed appropriate care plans, and managed discharges for incoming referrals in the psychiatric, geriatric, and home health settings

### SKILLS

#### Backend

Node.js / Express, Go, Ruby / Sinatra, Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### Cloud

Cloudflare (Workers, Durable Objects, Pages, Queues), Digital Ocean Droplets, fly.io

#### Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, jQuery, Handlebars.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap, HTML / CSS

#### Other

Git / Github, Linux, Bash, Jest, Minitest, Nginx, Rest APIs, GraphQL, Websockets

#### **EDUCATION**

<b>Launch School,</b> Software Engineering, Capstone Program  ☐ Multi-year, mastery-based curriculum teaching software engineering from first principles	2022 - 2024
University of Saint Augustine, Master's of Occupational Therapy	2015 - 2017
University of California - San Diego, B.S. General Biology	2009 - 2013